Michael Javier

9923 Edelweiss Circle Merriam, KS 66203 (913) 755-8133 <u>mikejavier82@gmail.com</u>

Summary:

I have been a developer for several years and have grown frustrated with the current state of tools for software developers, team documentation, and knowledge transfer. I would like to apply my web development skills to create more user-friendly systems for software development.

Technical Skills:

JavaScript, Angular, Node.js, npm, Linux, IntelliJ IDEA, Java, JUnit, REST API's, Spring, Maven, Git, PostgreSQL, Firewalls, JIRA, VirtualBox, HTML, Putty, ServiceNow Administration

Employment History:

FireMon LLC

Junior Software Developer

July 2019 to July 2022

- Maintained multiple Angular/Typescript components that were shared across several MVC web applications.
- Maintained REST API's for transferring data between front-end interfaces and Spring-managed backend services which persisted data to a Postgres database.
- Wrote unit and integration tests for code changes that I submitted.
- Helped design a customizable workflow editor user interface for our custom workflow framework.

Professional Services Engineer

January 2016 to July 2019

- Created dozens of custom workflow products for customers looking to use Firemon products to streamline their unique firewall change request process
- Assisted Solutions Architects in designing deliverable custom workflow solutions
- Met with customers to assist with configuration and troubleshooting of custom workflow solutions.
- Took ownership over a complex project to integrate Firemon's custom workflow framework to communicate with a third-party system (ServiceNow).
- Managed a multi-virtual machine environment for as many as 3 Professional Service Engineers

QA Tester

September 2013 to January 2016

- Wrote and executed manual test scripts for regression and functional testing of a Java web applications
- Learned technical specifications for networking devices in order to better understand and test software product
- Presented to new hires, other departments, and clients due to my technical expertise with the product.
- Worked closely with developers and network technicians to troubleshoot and diagnose bugs in the software.

Education:

Bachelors of Science: Computer Systems Engineering Technology, May 2012 GPA: 3.2 at Kansas State University Salina

References:

Jesse D'Angelo: Manager of Engineering - (785) 342-2625 **Dustin Gaito**: Professional Services Engineer - (785) 342-0170

Warren Smith: Software Engineer - (816) 529-4615